staffs.ac.uk 2004-12-08

# Privacy Statement

This privacy policy explains how we will treat your personal information. By using our website you consent to the collection and use of your information in accordance with this policy. The processing of personal information is regulated in the UK by the Data Protection Act 1998. You have a right to ask for a copy of the information we hold on you and to have information corrected if it is inaccurate. Please contact our Information Protection and Security Officer for further information. There is a statutory fee of £10 payable upon request.

Sue Howlett  
Information Protection & Security Manager  
Staffordshire University  
Stoke on Trent  
ST4 2DE  
 **Tel** : (0)1782 294365  
**Email** : [s.l.howlett@staffs.ac.uk](mailto:s.l.howlett@staffs.ac.uk)

## What information is collected?

  * Personal information given to us by you via on-line application form or requests for information will be used to provide you with information, goods or services you have requested such as prospectuses.  
The details you provide will not be used for marketing purposes unless you have been informed of this and have been given toe opportunity to opt-out of having your details used for this purpose.
  * Logging into our website on your machine IP address is collected automatically by the server.
  * Sometimes we may ask you to provide some limited further personal information about yourself to enable you to participate in services such as our alumni register or an e-payment facility. This information may include your name, title, address, telephone number and email address and may be stored manually or electronically.            

## What do we do with the information?

  * Any personal information that you provide to us will only be used for the purpose at the point when we request it and may be passed to appropriate employees of the University for that purpose. We will not sell, license or trade your personal information to others. We do not provide your personal information to direct marketing companies or other such organisations unless we have explicitly asked your permission to do so.
  * We may use your personal information for our own marketing purposes as laid down in the University's registration under the Data Protection Act 1998.
  * Using the logging data we may analyse demographic and other information to help us improve the efficiency and effectiveness of our website. Any analysis will be used for statistical purposes only and will not be capable of identifying you as an individual user.
